<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Javaday 2013</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Close</string>

    <string name="no_internet">No internet available</string>
    <string name="no_img_found">No IMG found</string>
    <string name="app_not_available">App not available</string>

    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="schedule">Schedule</string>
    <string name="speakers">Speakers</string>
    <string name="twitter">Twitter</string>

    <string-array name="navigation_drawer">
        <item>@string/home</item>
        <item>@string/schedule</item>
        <item>@string/speakers</item>
        <item>@string/twitter</item>
    </string-array>


    <string name="conf_title">Java Day Riga conference 2013</string>
    <string name="where">Kino Citadele</string>
    <string name="adress">13 Janvara st. 8, LV 1050 Riga, Latvia</string>
    <string name="when">Thu, Nov 28, 2013 8:30 AM - 7:00 PM</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>
    <string name="descripion_info">
        The conference is organised by Latvian Java User Group and Oracle at November 28th in Riga, Latvia.
        This is going to be a major Baltic IT event welcoming more than 250 Java programmers from the region.
        For any questions please contact Latvian JUG.
    </string>


    <!--speakers start-->

    <!--simon-->
    <string name="simon_ritter_name">Simon Ritter</string>
    <string name="simon_ritter_company">Oracle</string>
    <string name="simon_ritter_twitter">speakjava</string>
    <string name="simon_ritter_description">
        Simon Ritter is a Java Technology Evangelist at Oracle Corporation.
        Simon has been in the IT business since 1984 and holds a Bachelor of Science degree in Physics from Brunel University in the U.K.
        Originally working in the area of UNIX development for AT&amp;T UNIX System Labs and then Novell,
        Simon moved to Sun in 1996. At this time he started working with Java technology and has spent time working both in Java technology development and consultancy.
        Having moved to Oracle as part of the Sun acquisition he now focuses on the core Java platform, Java for client applications and embedded Java.
        He also continues to develop demonstrations that push the boundaries of Java for applications like gestural interfaces and embedded robot controllers.
        Follow him on Twitter, @speakjava and his blog at blogs.oracle.com/speakjava.</string>
    <string name="simon_ritter_presentation_title">
        Project Lambda: Functional Programming Constructs and Simpler Concurrency in Java SE 8</string>
    <string name="simon_ritter_presentation_description">
        The big language features for Java SE 8 are lambda expressions (closures) and default methods (formerly called
        defender methods or virtual extension methods). Adding lambda expressions to the language opens up a host of new
        expressive opportunities for applications and libraries. You might assume that lambda expressions are simply a
        more syntactically compact form of inner classes, but, in fact, the implementation of lambda expressions is
        substantially different and builds on the invokedynamic feature added in Java SE 7. This session will explain
        the ideas behind lambda expressions, how they will be used in Java SE 8 and look at some of the details of their
        implementation.
    </string>

    <!--cedric-->
    <string name="cedric_name">Cédric Champeau</string>
    <string name="cedric_company">Pivotal</string>
    <string name="cedric_twitter">CedricChampeau</string>
    <string name="cedric_description">
        Cédric Champeau is a core Groovy committer.
        He joined SpringSource, a division of VMware, in order to help developing the language.
        Prior to that, he spent several years at using Groovy in multiple industrial contexts including DSLs for natural language processing, scripting or even workflows.
        He worked on the implementation of static type checking and static compilation for Groovy 2.</string>
    <string name="cedric_presentation_title">10 years of Groovy!</string>
    <string name="cedric_presentation_description">
        The Groovy language has celebrated its 10th anniversary! First dynamic language on the JVM, with more than 1.7
        million downloads last year, it is still the most widely used alternative language on the JVM. With a low
        learning curve, especially for Java developers, it has lots of advantages and a long innovation tradition. If
        the concepts of closures, functional programming, DSLs, lambdas, scripting or type checking sound familiar to
        your ears, then come hear what Groovy 2.2 has to offer and join an active and passionate community!
    </string>

    <!--mirco-->
    <string name="mirco_dotta_name">Mirco Dotta</string>
    <string name="mirco_dotta_company">Typesafe</string>
    <string name="mirco_dotta_twitter">mircodotta</string>
    <string name="mirco_dotta_description">
        Mirco Dotta is a Software Engineer at Typesafe,
        building tools for the Scala language.
        He spends most of his time working on the Scala IDE for Eclipse and related ecosystem.
        His interests include concurrency, both OO and functional programming, software design, and testing.
        Mirco enjoys tweeting as @mircodotta. In his freetime, you\'ll often see him next to a foosball table.</string>
    <string name="mirco_dotta_presentation_title">Effective Scala</string>
    <string name="mirco_dotta_presentation_description">
        Everything you always wanted to know about Scala but were afraid to ask. If you want to be able to optimize your
        use of the Scala programming language to solve real world problems without explosions, broken thumbs or bullet
        wounds then this is the session for you. During the presentation there will be a lot of do\'s and don\'t\'s in
        order to guide you into how to become a better Scala developer. The target audience is intermediate to advanced
        Scala developers.
    </string>

    <!--tero-->
    <string name="tero_name">Tero Parviainen</string>
    <string name="tero_company">Independent</string>
    <string name="tero_twitter">teropa</string>
    <string name="tero_description">Tero Parviainen is an independent software maker with 12 years of professional yak shaving under the belt.
        During this time he has worn many different hats, ranging from consultant to startup CTO.
        His weapons of choice are Clojure, JavaScript, Java, and Ruby.
        Tero is currently putting together the Clojure Cup programming competition and has also just finished writing a book
        called Real-time Web Application Development with Vert.x 2.0.</string>
    <string name="tero_presentation_title">Immutable Java</string>
    <string name="tero_presentation_description">
        Following the rise of Clojure, many of us have become aware of the idea of immutable data structures and their
        benefits. In Clojure, all built-in data structures are immutable, and the same also applies to everything we
        build out of them. This has profound effects on how programs are constructed and transforms the way we can
        reason about them, test them, compose them, and deploy them into concurrent environments. But what is the
        immutability story in Java? Is immutability just a Clojure or a functional thing, or does it apply to the type
        of OO programs we build with Java? If we do want to utilize immutable data in Java, how should we go about it?
        What built-in APIs can we use and what should we stay away from? What libraries are there to help us? How should
        we construct our programs - in the small and in the large? This talk surveys the current state of immutable data
        in Java, comparing and contrasting it to Clojure
    </string>

    <!--patraklos-->
    <string name="patroklos_name">Patroklos Papapetrou</string>
    <string name="patroklos_company">FoodTec Solutions Inc.</string>
    <string name="patroklos_twitter">ppapapetrou76</string>
    <string name="patroklos_description">Patroklos Papapetrou is a Java architect,
        addicted to software quality and an agile team leader with more than 15 years of experience in software development.
        He believes and invests in people and team spirit seeking quality excellence.
        He\'s co-authoring Sonar in action book, he is an active Sonar community member and plugin contributor.
        He treats software systems as flowers that\'s why he prefers calling himself a software gardener.</string>
    <string name="patroklos_presentation_title">Tracking and Improving Software Quality with Sonar</string>
    <string name="patroklos_presentation_description">
        Software quality is about a lot more than slinging good code. As a java developer you use numerous tools,
        techniques and frameworks as you write, organize, build, test, refactor, and continuously improve your
        applications. Sonar, a free and open source quality platform, makes it radically easier to track, manage, and
        enhance the overall quality of your code. In this presentation I\'m going to talk about Sonar\'s core ideas, and
        its star features that simplify the process of tracking and improving software quality.
    </string>

    <!--kuksenko-->
    <string name="kuksenko_name">Sergey Kuksenko</string>
    <string name="kuksenko_company">Oracle</string>
    <string name="kuksenko_twitter">kuksenk0</string>
    <string name="kuksenko_description">Sergey is Java Performance Engineer working for Oracle.
        His primary skills are performance engineering, benchmarking, JVMs, JIT compilers, and class libraries.
        He’s been accelerating JVMs since 2005 when he was worked for Intel in Apache Harmony performance team.</string>
    <string name="kuksenko_presentation_title">JDK8: Stream style</string>
    <string name="kuksenko_presentation_description">
        JDK8 is bringing lambdas into the Java world. But without significant Java SE 8 libraries extensions lambdas
        would be only a toy. The centerpiece of the new libraries is the Streams API (formerly ‘Collections bulk
        operations’). This session presents the Streams API and examples how to get the best performance and scalability
        using the library.
    </string>

    <!--sizov-->
    <string name="sizov_name">Eduard Sizov</string>
    <string name="sizov_company">4finance</string>
    <string name="sizov_twitter">eduardsi</string>
    <string name="sizov_description">Eduards is software craftsman passionate about every aspect of software development.
        His interests include lightweight architectures, clean code, domain-driven design, automation,
        continuous delivery and other spices. Being a Chief Software Architect in 4finance,
        he is responsible for building a premier kick-ass financial platform speaking Java,
        running in the form of various products around the globe.</string>
    <string name="sizov_presentation_title">Micro Service Architecture</string>
    <string name="sizov_presentation_description">
        Eduards will talk about micro service architecture - approach to designing software when complex app is broken
        into tiny, cohesive services which are apps themselves. Anatomy of micro services will be covered with practical
        implementation advices in Java.
    </string>

    <!--gulati-->
    <string name="gulati_name">Shekhar Gulati</string>
    <string name="gulati_company">Red Hat</string>
    <string name="gulati_twitter">shekhargulati</string>
    <string name="gulati_description">Shekhar Gulati is Principal OpenShift Developer Evangelist working with Red Hat.
        He has 8 years of software web development experience. He regularly speaks at various conference and user groups around the world.
        Shekhar is an active writer and has written many technical articles for IBM DeveloperWorks, Developer.com, and JavaLobby.
        His current interests are NoSQL databases, cloud computing, mainly Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS), mobile development,
        javascript frameworks, and new things happening in Java community.
        When he is not traveling, he loves to write code and read technology books. You can follow him on twitter @ shekhargulati.</string>
    <string name="gulati_presentation_title">Thinking Beyond RDBMS : Building Polyglot Persistence Java Applications</string>
    <string name="gulati_presentation_description">
        Time has come to start thinking about multiple data storage solutions while building applications. A single
        application can use multiple data storage technologies depending on its use case - right tool for right job.
        The session will start by introducing polyglot persistence to the audience. Next we will cover the pros and cons
        of Polyglot persistence. Then we will see how to build location aware Job search application using MongoDB,
        PostgreSQL, Redis, and Solr. The different data storage solutions are used to persist different types of data
        like MongoDB to store Job data along with its location, PostgreSQL to store User data, Redis as a cache for User
        objects and other goodies, and Solr as a full text search engine. Finally, the application will be deployed to
        OpenShift - open source Platform as a Service.
    </string>

    <!--valenta-->
    <string name="valenta_name">Jan Valenta</string>
    <string name="valenta_company">Oracle</string>
    <string name="valenta_twitter"></string>
    <string name="valenta_description">Jan Valenta has been developing physics algorithms and
        designing user interface for experiments at CERN before he joined Sun Microsystems in 2006.
        At Sun, he contributed to Java Wireless Toolkit project, participated on the SVG Tiny implementation and low level renderer development.
        In the JavaFX area, he worked on support for hardware accelerated devices and recently focuses on
        tools support, deployment, and javadoc doclet.</string>
    <string name="valenta_presentation_title">JavaFX Deployment</string>
    <string name="valenta_presentation_description">
        The presentation focuses on two aspects of publishing JavaFX applications and libraries: learn how to deploy
        JavaFX applications in 4 scenarios and how to easily document JavaFX code for library users. The session covers
        JavaFX deployment in form of runnable Java archives, web start technology, regular applets, and native
        executables using either NetBeans IDE, ANT scripts or plain command line tools on all JavaFX platforms. The
        second part of the session shows how to document your JavaFX library code using the JavaFX javadoc doclet which
        provides a set of useful JavaFX-specific features to ease JavaFX code documentation.
    </string>

    <!--palka-->
    <string name="jaroslaw_palka_name">Jarosław Pałka</string>
    <string name="jaroslaw_palka_company">Lumesse</string>
    <string name="jaroslaw_palka_twitter">j_palka</string>
    <string name="jaroslaw_palka_description">Jarek spent last 15 years of his life in IT working as database and system administrator,
        developer, architect, manager and "on site disaster engineer ".
        He was involved in small, medium and horribly and nonsense large systems,
        from "waterfall" through Agile to "no methodology" methodology.
        It all lead him to conclusion that it doesn\'t matter what you do as long as you do it right,
        keep it simple and use the right tool to do the job for you. In the meantime he fell in love it TDD,
        Software Craftmanship and beautiful and simple ideas like REST, JavaScript and NOSQL.
        From time to time you can hear his low quality jokes about architecture on conferences in Poland.
        He is trying to make a world a better place as member of SSEEP and blog author at http://geekyprimitives.wordpress.com.</string>
    <string name="jaroslaw_palka_presentation_title">Practical Spring Data</string>
    <string name="jaroslaw_palka_presentation_description">
        Spring Data is an \'umbrella\' project, developed by SpringSource community, which easies development of
        applications while working with different database models. From relational databases over "good old" JDBC,
        through O/R mappings with a little bit of help from JPA, to hottest and newest NoSQL databases, which span from
        key-value, document to graph databases. Spring Data simplifies connectivity with variety of databases, provides
        unified programming model and patterns.It also frees you from writing boilerplate code by promoting convention
        over coding and extensive use of runtime generated code. Thanks to this you can focus on building valid and
        complete domain models with less annoying errors in your data access layer, which results in higher quality code
        delivered in less time. During this presentation you will get familiar with four different data models,
        including O/R mappings (JPA 2.0), key-value stores (Redis), document databases (MongoDB) and graph databases
        (Neo4j). You will understand how Spring Data works undercover, and how different data models fit into modern web
        applications and how to work "polyglot persistance" concept.
    </string>

    <!--zeeb-->
    <string name="zeeb_name">Nick Zeeb</string>
    <string name="zeeb_company">LMAX</string>
    <string name="zeeb_twitter">NickZeeb</string>
    <string name="zeeb_description">Nick Zeeb is a core Java developer at LMAX Exchange in London.
        LMAX operates a financial exchange that is capable of handling 20,000 orders per second with a
        mean latency of 1.5 milliseconds. Nick has been involved in the financial industry since 2006 and
        has seen some interesting times while working at a hedge fund, an investment bank and now an exchange.</string>
    <string name="zeeb_presentation_title">High Performance Design</string>
    <string name="zeeb_presentation_description">
        When economic news comes out, trading volumes spike and the LMAX Exchange needs to push out the latest prices to
        all of our clients as fast as possible. This presentation is about how we solved this problem by using Test
        Driven Design. It will show, step by step, how we created a lock-free, high performance data structure by using
        knowledge of how modern processors are designed.
    </string>

    <!--fedorov-->
    <string name="fedorov_name">Alexey Fedorov</string>
    <string name="fedorov_company">Oracle</string>
    <string name="fedorov_twitter">23derevo</string>
    <string name="fedorov_description">Alexey graduated Saint-Petersburg State University,
        where he defended his diploma and PhD thesis on the theory of dynamical systems.
        He works in Oracle, Java Platform group, Java Compatibility Kit (JCK).
        Alexey is one of the leaders of the St. Petersburg Java User Group and cross-technology community CodeFreeze.
        Also he is one of the organizers of the St. Petersburg Java-conferences JPoint and Joker.</string>
    <string name="fedorov_presentation_title">Java platform trade-offs</string>
    <string name="fedorov_presentation_description">
        As with any software, the Java Platform is existing and developing under tight restrictions. Therefore, Java
        platform developers constantly have to make difficult choices and make decisions. The talk is about Java
        Platform tradeoffs: why the choice is inevitable and that is a matter of choice.
    </string>

    <!--luciano-->
    <string name="luciano_name">Luciano Fiandesio</string>
    <string name="luciano_company">Aestas/IT</string>
    <string name="luciano_twitter"></string>
    <string name="luciano_description">Luciano Fiandesio is a programmer, technology enthusiast and entrepreneur living in Zurich, Switzerland.
        Luciano has been working for the last 18 years in 12 different countries as architect and developer for large
        corporations and small start-ups: Nokia, European Central Bank, BNP Paribas, Ericsson are among his clients.
        He loves coding and designing solutions that are both elegant and rock solid. When not busy learning the next big thing,
        he likes playing with his analogue cameras and cooking Italian food.
        Two years ago he started a consulting company focused on software factory automation, Aestas IT, where Groovy plays a big role.
        He holds a Master Degree in Literature and Philosophy from Rome University.</string>
    <string name="luciano_presentation_title">Groovy DevOps in the Cloud</string>
    <string name="luciano_presentation_description">
        This talk focuses on a set of tools to automate the provisioning of virtual machines on Amazon EC2 using Groovy
        programming language and libraries. We will explore how to leverage those to create an infrastructure for
        building, configuring and testing the provisioning of boxes in the cloud - elegant and groovy.
    </string>

    <!--antipin-->
    <string name="antipin_name">Roman Antipin</string>
    <string name="antipin_company">Odnoklassniki</string>
    <string name="antipin_twitter"></string>
    <string name="antipin_description">Roman is a leading developer at Odnoklassniki since 2010.
        As a platform team member, he is engaged in the development and implementation of distributed storage systems.
        Before joining Odnoklassniki team he gained distributed systems experience developing server side of a real-time
        network distributed monitoring system at Devexperts company.</string>
    <string name="antipin_presentation_title">Managing highly concurrent data at Odnoklassniki</string>
    <string name="antipin_presentation_description">
        Odnoklassniki use Voldemort based data storages to manage data having high concurrency and extreme availability
        access requirements. We cover why and how we migrated from our old, Berkeley DB based storage solution, why
        Voldemort seems the best solution here (beating even Cassandra!) and why we replaced storage engine of Voldemort
        again and again to meet our tight requirements.
    </string>

    <!--Magda-->
    <string name="magda_name">Denis Magda</string>
    <string name="magda_company">Oracle</string>
    <string name="magda_twitter"></string>
    <string name="magda_description">Denis is a technical lead of Java ME Embedded porting team at Oracle.
        The team is responsible for the Java ME Embedded porting process on wide variety of systems on a chip,
        micro controllers and other constrained devices. Before Denis moved its interest
        into the small embedded world he was working as a member of Java ME Multimedia team at Oracle for several years.</string>
    <string name="magda_presentation_title">Modernize Your Home or Garage with Java ME Embedded</string>
    <string name="magda_presentation_description">
        Modern technologies are everywhere in our life, but do you know how to use them? Have you ever tried to automate
        something in your house? Maybe you dream of creating a robot or another automated mechanism but the task seems
        too complex for you? Java ME Embedded is a new generation of the well-known Java ME platform that aims to bring
        a simple and unified way to develop applications for embedded systems. In this session, you will learn how it is
        easy to get information from different sensors and control a variety of peripheral devices with Java’s device
        access API library. The session includes a step-by-step guide that enables you to start automating your life
        with Java ME Embedded.
    </string>

    <!--Andrey Adamovich-->
    <string name="adamovich_name">Andrey Adamovich</string>
    <string name="adamovich_company">Aestas IT</string>
    <string name="adamovich_twitter"></string>
    <string name="adamovich_description">Andrey Adamovich is a software craftsman with many years of experience in
        different lifecycle phases of software creation. He is passionate about defining good development practices,
        documenting and presenting architecture, reuse of code and design patterns, profiling and analysis of
        application performance as well as extreme automation of development and operations activities. Andrey has
        Master Degree in Computer Science from Latvian State University.
    </string>

    <!--speakers end-->
</resources>
